Here's an example.
例を 見てみましょう
Imagine your network is a stack of simple operations;
ネットワークが 単純な演算の スタックだとしましょう
like linear transforms, ReLUs, whatever you want.
線形変換とか ReLUとか 何でもいいです
Some have parameters, like the matrix transforms,
行列変換のように パラメーターを 持つものもあれば
some don't, like the ReLUs.
ReLUのように 持たないものもあります
When you apply your data to some input x,
入力のxに データを適用すると
you have data flowing through the stack up to your predictions y.
データは スタックの中を 通って 予測yに 到達します
To compute the derivatives,
微分係数を 計算するために
you create another graph that looks like this.
こんな感じの グラフを 別に作成します
The data in that new graph flows backwards through the network,
新しいグラフのデータは ネットワーク内を 逆方向に流れ
gets combined using the chain rule that we saw before, and produces gradients.
先ほど見た 連鎖法則を使って 組み合わされ 勾配を生成します
That graph can be derived completely automatically
このグラフは ネットワーク内の 個々の演算から
from the individual operations in your network.
自動的に 導き出すことができます
So, most deep learning frameworks will just do it for you.
そのため ほとんどのディープラーニングフレームワークで 自動的に行われています
This is called back propagation and it's a very powerful concept.
これは 逆伝播という とても強力な 概念です
It makes computing derivatives of complex function very efficient,
複雑な関数の 微分係数の計算が とても効率的になります
as long as the function is made up of simple blocks with simple derivatives.
ただし 関数が 単純な微分係数を含む 単純なブロックで 構成されていることが 条件です
Running the model up to the predictions is often called the forward prop.
予測まで モデルを実行するプロセスを 順伝播と いいます
And the model that goes backwards is called the back prop.
そして モデルを逆方向に 実行するプロセスを 逆伝播といいます
So to recap, to run stochastic gradient descent.
まとめると 確率的勾配降下法を 実行するには
For every single little batch of your data in your training set,
トレーニングセットの データの バッチごとに
you're going to run the forward prop and then the back prop.
順伝播と 逆伝播を 実行します
And that will give you gradient for each of your weights in your model.
これにより モデルの それぞれの重みの 勾配が 得られます
Then you're going to apply those gradients with learning
次に 求めた勾配を 学習率に従って
rates to your original weights and update them.
元の重みに 適用し 更新します
And you're going to repeat that all over again many, many times.
そして この作業を 最初から 何度も何度も 繰り返します
This is how your entire model gets optimized.
それにより モデルが 最適化されていきます
I'm not going to go through more of the math of what's going on in each of those blocks,
それぞれの ブロックで どのような計算が 行われるかは 説明しません
because again you don't typically have to worry about that.
なぜなら 普通は 気にする必要がなく
And it's essentially the chain rule.
基本的には 連鎖法則だからです
But keep in mind this diagram.
大切なのは この図です
In particular, each block of the back prop often takes
特に 逆伝播のブロックは 順伝播の
about twice the memory that's needed for the forward prop and twice to compute.
2倍のメモリーを 必要とし 2倍量の計算を 行います
That's important when you want to size your model and fit in memory for example.
このことは たとえば メモリーに合わせて モデルのサイズを決定するときに 重要です